<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Frederick Solt</title>
    <link>http://fsolt.org/tags/r.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Frederick Solt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://fsolt.org/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The SWIID Source Data</title>
      <link>http://fsolt.org/blog/2017/07/27/the-swiid-source-data.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fsolt.org/blog/2017/07/27/the-swiid-source-data.html</guid>
      <description>I have been producing the Standardized World Income Inequality Database for nearly a decade. Since 2008, the SWIID has provided estimates of the Gini index of income inequality1 for as many countries and years as possible and–given the primary goal of maximizing spatial and temporal coverage–these estimates are as comparable as the available data allow. The dataset has been used widely by academics, journalists, and policymakers. It’s been successful way beyond all my hopes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>icpsrdata makes your ICPSR downloads reproducible!</title>
      <link>http://fsolt.org/blog/2016/05/20/icpsrdata.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 22:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fsolt.org/blog/2016/05/20/icpsrdata.html</guid>
      <description>If you download data from the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research archive archive, you can make your research reproducible with the icpsrdata package, now available on CRAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try pewdata!</title>
      <link>http://fsolt.org/blog/2016/05/13/pewdata.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fsolt.org/blog/2016/05/13/pewdata.html</guid>
      <description>If you use Pew Research Center surveys, you can make your research reproducible with the pewdata package now available on CRAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use dotwhisker for your APSA slides!</title>
      <link>http://fsolt.org/blog/2015/07/30/dotwhisker-for-apsa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 10:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fsolt.org/blog/2015/07/30/dotwhisker-for-apsa.html</guid>
      <description>With the APSA coming up, and in the interest of minimizing the number of times we hear &amp;ldquo;sorry, I know you won&amp;rsquo;t really be able to see these regression coefficients,&amp;rdquo; I thought I&amp;rsquo;d point R users to dotwhisker, a package UI Ph.D. student Yue HU and I just published to CRAN. dotwhisker makes regression plots in the style of Kastellec and Leoni&amp;rsquo;s (2007) Perspectives article quick and easy: after data entry, just two lines of R code produced the easy-to-read-even-from-the-back-of-the-room plot attached to this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now on CRAN: interplot</title>
      <link>http://fsolt.org/blog/2015/06/26/now-on-cran-interplot.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 09:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fsolt.org/blog/2015/06/26/now-on-cran-interplot.html</guid>
      <description>Hu Yue and I just published interplot on CRAN, our first R package. interplot makes graphing the coefficients of variables in interaction terms easy. It outputs ggplot objects, so further customization is simple. Check out the vignette and give it a try!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>